Eric Vincent

4237 Manuela Ave | Palo Alto, CA 94306 | evincent@gmail.com | egvincent.github.io | 650 468 0664

Education Stanford University

Class of 2020

Stanford, CA

Selected completed courses:

- CS 106X: Programming Abstractions Accelerated (advanced C++ foundational course in algorithms and data structures)
- CS 110: Principles of Computer Systems (filesystems, concurrency, networking)
- CS 246: Mining Massive Data Sets (big data systems, similarity search, stream data processing, dimensionality reduction, large scale machine learning, and more)

Henry M. Gunn High School

Class of 2016

Palo Alto, CA

Selected completed courses: AP Biology, AP AB Calculus, Programming Concepts (used Scheme), Introduction to Java, AP French, AP Micro/Macroeconomics

GPA: 3.79 unweighted, 3.96 weighted

SAT: 730 reading, 700 math, 760 writing (2190 total)

Institute for Mathematics and Computer Science 2013 - 2014 Online AP Computer Science: Java Programming (not allowed for sophomores at Gunn HS) *Grade:* A+, *AP Test Score:* 5 out of 5

Experience

<u>Microsoft Azure Media Services</u> SWE Intern Summer of 2018 Redmond, WA Media Services provides enterprise video encoding, streaming, analytics, and more.

- Improved security token validation (prior to key/license delivery) by adding new options for limited reuse tokens and a DRM-independent active device limit
- Used: C# with JWT & SWT tokens

DeepMap SWE Intern Summer of 2017 Palo Alto, CA DeepMap provides high definition 3D mapping as a service for self-driving cars.

- Built systems for robust ground and car detection in sparse LiDAR point clouds
- Built systems for object tracking and velocity estimation across multiple point clouds
- Used: C++

Savioke SWE Intern Summer of 2016 San Jose, CA Savioke builds the Relay, an autonomous, user-friendly room service robot for hotels.

- Enabled Relay robot to call external APIs
- Connected Relay to Amazon Alexa and the Amazon IOT Button
- Explored new interactive uses for Relay by extending a visual robot scripting interface.
- Used: AWS, JavaScript with MeteorJS and ROS, Google Blockly

<u>Metanautix</u> (acquired by Microsoft) SWE Intern Summer of 2015 Palo Alto, CA Enterprise software company focused on big data management, analytics, and visualization.

- Worked as a front-end web developer on their multi-database query tool, Quest
- Used: AngularJS and Bootstrap

<u>Camio</u> SWE Intern Summer of 2014 San Mateo, CA

Smart, cloud-based video monitoring and analytics for the home.

- Built a system to automatically graph core company metrics
- Used: JavaScript and Google BigQuery with SQL

Programming Skills

Core: proficient in C++ and experienced with Java and C#; wrote clean and efficient C++ code in four separate Stanford courses and a summer software engineering internship Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, AngularJS, MeteorJS, HTTP(S)

Scripting: Python, Bash

Comfortable with Git (and in conjunction with GitHub, Gerrit, or CodeFlow)

Activities **Competitive Gymnastics**

2007 - 2016

Stanford Boys Gymnastics, San Mateo Gymnastics

I was a competitive gymnast for nine years. I practiced ~20 hours per week year round. I was team captain from 2015 to 2016.

Highlights:

Level 10 (2016) – JO Nationals: 5th place and all around finals. Regionals: 6th place and all-star team. States: 2nd place and all-star team.

Level 9 (2011-2013) - JO Nationals all three years, event finals on floor and pommel horse Level 6 (2009) – 4th place at State Championships, 1st place at Regional Championships.

Gunn Robotics Team

2014 - 2016

www.gunnrobotics.com

I was a member of my school's student-run FIRST robotics team for two years, and a member of the team's control systems group for one year. I have experience machining on a mill, lathe, drill press, band saw, and many other shop tools. In the controls team, I wrote python code to access several sensors and to control several mechanisms on the robot. I was an active member, and contributed upwards of 10 hours per week in addition to attending the competitions, helping our team win the FRC Team Spirit Award in 2016. In addition to coding and machining, I have written content for our team's website and business plan and have experience with CAD and basic electrical engineering.

Ecole Nationale du Cirque

2010 - 2012

ecolenationaledecirque.ca/en

I was accepted at the prestigious "National Circus School" in Montreal, Canada for three consecutive summers. While at the school I improved my skills in hand balancing, unicycling, and learned the German Wheel, Silks, and other disciplines of circus arts.

Graphic Arts, Stanford Open

2011 - 2015

egvincent.com/stanford-open

For 5 consecutive years, I designed the T-shirt and logo for the "Stanford Open," an annual three-day gymnastics competition my gym hosts for over 800 gymnasts and their families.

Δ	۱A	ıa	rd	e
_	w	ď	ıu	

AP Scholar with Distinction	2016	
-----------------------------	------	--

CollegeBoard

Outstanding Accomplishments 2015 in the Visual Arts

Gunn High School

Academic All American

Recognition Award

2015: First Team honors

2014: Second Team honors

USA Gymnastics

French National Contest

2013 (2C): Lauréat du Chapitre The American Association

and Certificat d'Honneur

of Teachers of French